[{"Question":"Has the deadline for federal taxes changed?","Current Answer":"","Proposed revised question":"no change","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"no change","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/taxes/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"84"},{"Question":"Are there any tax deductions for people affected by the COVID-19 outbreak?","Current Answer":"No. Check with the [U.S. Internal Revenue Service](https://www.irs.gov/coronavirus), the [California Franchise Tax Board](https://www.ftb.ca.gov/), and your local government for updates.","Proposed revised question":"no change","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"no change","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/taxes/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"87"},{"Question":"Can the Order be changed?","Current Answer":"Yes. The State Public Health Officer may issue new orders as the public health situation changes.","Proposed revised question":"Can the stay home order be changed?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"91"},{"Question":"How does this order interact with local orders to shelter in place? Does it supersede them?","Current Answer":"This is a statewide order. Counties may open additional Stage 2 sectors more quickly if they meet certain criteria.","Proposed revised question":"How does the Stay Home Order interact with local orders? Does it override them?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"92"},{"Question":"If I am not an Essential Critical Infrastructure Worker, can I still leave the house?","Current Answer":"Yes. As described in more detail elsewhere in applicable state public health directives (including on this page), there are a wide range of circumstances in which you may leave your home or other place of residence, even if you are not an Essential Critical Infrastructure Worker.For example, you may leave your home to work at any business or other entity that is allowed to open, to patronize local businesses, or to care for friends or family members who require assistance (as set forth below).And errands like these are not the only reasons you may leave your home: you may also leave your home with or without a specific destination in mind (for example, to walk your dog, to engage in physical recreation, or simply to get some fresh air) as long as you maintain physical distancing and **do not gather with any number of people who are not members of your household.**\\n\\n### Protected activities","Proposed revised question":"Can I leave my house if I am not an essential worker or if my job industry has not reopened?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"93"},{"Question":"How do I vote?","Current Answer":"Elections are an essential activity, and the [Governor has issued executive orders to ensure elections are safe and accessible](https://www.gov.ca.gov/2020/05/08/governor-newsom-issues-executive-order-to-protect-public-health-by-mailing-every-registered-voter-a-ballot-ahead-of-the-november-general-election/). Vote-by-mail ballots will be sent to all registered voters for the November 3, 2020 General Election. The Secretary of State and the California Department of Public Health are working on additional guidance to ensure that all Californians are able to participate in elections safely. Existing laws address the use of vote-by-mail ballots in California elections, and those laws remain in effect unless otherwise noted.\\n\\nOf course, whenever you engage in any permissible activity—including the collection and drop-off of ballots, or other election-related activities—be mindful of physical distancing and other measures to protect yourself and those around you.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"95"},{"Question":"Can I practice my religious faith?","Current Answer":"Yes. Practicing your faith is a constitutionally-protected activity and may manifest in many different forms.\\n\\nAlthough in-person religious gatherings—like other in-person gatherings—have been restricted to prevent the transmission of COVID-19, on May 25, 2020, the State Public Health Officer  began to ease restrictions on in-person religious gatherings. In particular, the State Public Health Officer now authorizes County Departments of Public Health to allow collective activities at places of worship, subject to conditions to support a safe, clean environment for employees, interns and trainees, volunteers, scholars, and all other types of workers as well as congregants, worshippers, and visitors.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"church, worship, religion, religious, faith, gathering","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"96"},{"Question":"What conditions must be met to resume religious services at places of worship?","Current Answer":"Full information on conditions imposed by the state can be found at[ guidance for places of worship.](https://covid19.ca.gov/pdf/guidance-places-of-worship.pdf) Additionally conditions may be imposed by local public health officials. This guidance does not obligate places of worship to resume in-person activity and it is strongly recommended that places of worship continue to facilitate remote services and other alternatives to in-person religious practice for those who are vulnerable to COVID19.\\n\\nEven with adherence to physical distancing, convening in a congregational setting of multiple different households to practice a personal faith carries a higher risk of widespread transmission of COVID-19, and may result in increased rates of infection, hospitalization, and death, especially among more vulnerable populations. In particular, activities like singing and group recitation dramatically increase the risk of COVID-19 transmission. For this reason, congregants engaging in singing, particularly in the choir, and group recitation should wear face coverings at all times.\\n\\nPlaces of worship must therefore limit attendance to 25% of building capacity or a maximum of 100 attendees, whichever is lower. This limitation will be in effect for the first 21-days of a county public health department’s approval of religious services and cultural ceremonies activities at places of worship within their jurisdictions.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"church, worship, religion, religious, faith, gathering","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"97"},{"Question":"Can children attend group activities (like Sunday school or Hebrew school) at places of worship?","Current Answer":"At this time, no.  Children should remain in the care of those in their household unit and not interact with children of other parties at all times while visiting facilities. Additionally, places of worship must discontinue activities and services for children (including, for example, shared play areas) where physical distancing of at least six feet cannot be maintained.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"Sunday school, church, worship, religion, religious, faith, gathering","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"98"},{"Question":"When will these conditions change for places of worship?","Current Answer":"Every 21 days, the California Department of Public Health, in consultation with county Departments of Public Health, will review and assess the impacts of these imposed limits on public health and provide further direction as part of a phased-in restoration of activities in places of worship. This is because COVID-19 has an incubation period of 14 days; the 21-day interval accounts for this incubation period and provides for an additional seven days for thorough review, analysis, and preparation of modifications.","Proposed revised question":"When will the limits for places of worship be lifted?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"church, worship, religion, religious, faith, gathering","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"99"},{"Question":"Can I still exercise? Take my kids to the park for fresh air? Take a walk around the block?","Current Answer":"It’s okay to go outside to go for a walk, to exercise, and participate in healthy activities as long as you **maintain a safe physical distance of six feet and gather only with members of your household.** Below is a list of some outdoor recreational activities.\\n\\n*Parks may be closed to help slow the spread of the virus. Check with local officials about park closures in your area. Californians should not travel significant distances and should stay close to home.\\n\\n*   Athletics\\n\\n*   Badminton (singles)\\n\\n*   Throwing a baseball/softball\\n\\n*   BMX biking\\n\\n*   Canoeing (singles)\\n\\n*   Crabbing\\n\\n*   Cycling\\n\\n*   Exploring rock pools\\n\\n*   Gardening (not in groups)\\n\\n*   Golfing (singles, with carts)\\n\\n*   Hiking (trails/ paths allowing distancing)\\n\\n*   Horse riding (singles)\\n\\n*   Jogging and running\\n\\n*   Kite boarding and kitesurfing\\n\\n*   Meditation\\n\\n*   Outdoor photography\\n\\n*   Picnics (with your household members only)\\n\\n*   Quad biking\\n\\n*   Rock climbing\\n\\n*   Roller skating and rollerblading\\n\\n*   Rowing (singles)\\n\\n*   Scootering (not in groups)\\n\\n*   Skateboarding (not in groups)\\n\\n*   Soft martial arts – tai chi, chi kung (not in groups)\\n\\n*   Surfing\\n\\n*   Tennis and table tennis (singles)\\n\\n*   Throwing a football, kicking a soccer ball (not in groups)\\n\\n*   Trail running\\n\\n*   Trampolining\\n\\n*   Tree climbing\\n\\n*   Volleyball (singles)\\n\\n*   Walk the dog\\n\\n*   Wash the car\\n\\n*   Watch the sunrise or sunset\\n\\n*   Yoga","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"exercise, park,","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"111"},{"Question":"Can I walk my dog? Take my pet to the vet?","Current Answer":"You can walk your dog. You can go to the vet or pet hospital if your pet is sick. Remember to distance yourself at least six feet from other pets and owners.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"pet, pets, vet, veternarian,","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"112"},{"Question":"Can I visit State Parks? What outdoor spaces are open?","Current Answer":"State Parks, campgrounds, museums, and visitor centers have been closed to help slow the spread of the virus. A list of all closures can be found at [www.parks.ca.gov/flattenthecurve](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__www.parks.ca.gov_flattenthecurve&d=DwMGaQ&c=Lr0a7ed3egkbwePCNW4ROg&r=yRsi0eKVK6Khc58oFC32XROAJ-JqVGBGabDv9P6148k&m=_fPxTmPUxMvOIT4dV-3Qeb4cjflv8ev1xNzeyjEJEu8&s=vM7KqvLoqg2j3Owj0qT1KhF7RlcZWasPwWAbbnYfiGo&e=). See a list of outdoor spaces that are open on the [Public recreation](https://covid19.ca.gov/public-recreation) page.\\n\\nYou can walk, run, hike and bike in your local neighborhoods as long as they continue to practice social distancing of 6 feet. This means avoiding crowded trails & parking lots. Californians should not travel significant distances and should stay close to home.\\n\\nFor information on National Parks, please the [National Park Service website](https://www.nps.gov/aboutus/news/public-health-update.htm).\\n\\n### Government services","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"state parks, state park, outdoors, exercise, recreation, beach, outdoor, go out","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"113"},{"Question":"Can I go to the Department of Motor Vehicles (DMV)?","Current Answer":"Starting May 8, [25 select DMV offices](https://www.dmv.ca.gov/portal/dmv/detail/pubs/newsrel/2020/2020_19) are open to the public to help with appointments that require an in-person visit. You will be required to wear a cloth mask and must remain 6 feet apart in line. In-person appointments are limited to:\\n\\n*   Paying registration for a vehicle impounded because of registration-related issues\\n\\n*   Reinstating a suspended or revoked driver license\\n\\n*   Applying for a reduced-fee or no-fee identification card\\n\\n*   Processing commercial driver license transactions\\n\\n*   Applying for a disabled person parking placards\\n\\n*   Adding an ambulance certificate or firefighter endorsement to a driver license\\n\\n*   Verifying a transit training document to drive a transit bus\\n\\n*   Processing DMV Express customers for REAL ID transactions, if time and space allows\\n\\nDMV services that do not require an in-person office visit can be accessed through the [DMV Virtual Field Office](https://virtual.dmv.ca.gov/), including driver’s license renewals, vehicle registrations, title changes, and more.\\n\\nDMV has extended deadlines for:\\n\\n*   All drivers licenses expiring between March 1 through May 31, 2020\\n\\n    *   Drivers 70 years of age and older will receive a 120-day paper extension\\n\\n    *   Drivers 69 years of age and younger can request a free temporary [extension online](https://virtual.dmv.ca.gov/temporary-driver-license-request/)\\n\\n*   Expiring commercial licenses, endorsements, and certificates are valid through June 30, 2020\\n\\n*   In-person renewals for vehicle registrations that expire between the dates of March 16, 2020, and May 31, 2020.\\n\\n*   In-person renewals for those with safe driving records whose last DMV visit was 15 years ago","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"DMV, government, government offices,","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"114"},{"Question":"Should I use cloth face coverings or masks to protect against COVID-19?","Current Answer":"Yes,  when you must leave home to conduct activities permitted under the current roadmap stage, you should wear a cloth face covering or mask. The California Department of Public Health (CDPH) has released [Guidance on Use of Cloth Face Coverings](https://www.cdph.ca.gov/Programs/CID/DCDC/Pages/Face-Coverings-Guidance.aspx).\\n\\nThe cloth face coverings recommended are **not **medical grade respirators, such as N95 and surgical masks.\\n\\nThe guidance reminds Californians that the best defense against COVID-19 continues to be: \\n\\n*   Staying at home and physical distancing \\n\\n*   Washing hands frequently\\n\\n*   Avoiding touching eyes, nose and mouth with unwashed hands\\n\\n*   Avoiding being around people with COVID-19 symptoms\\n\\nThe use of cloth face coverings could reduce the transmission of COVID-19 by individuals who do not have symptoms and may reinforce physical distancing.","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Cloth face covering, Mask, PPE","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"115"},{"Question":"What is a cloth face covering?","Current Answer":"A cloth face covering is [material that covers the nose and mouth](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prevent-getting-sick/diy-cloth-face-coverings.html). It can be secured to the head with ties or straps or simply wrapped around the lower face. It can be made of a variety of materials, such as cotton, silk, or linen. A cloth face covering may be factory-made or sewn by hand, or can be improvised from household items such as scarfs, T-shirts, sweatshirts, or towels.","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Cloth face covering, Mask, PPE","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"116"},{"Question":"How should I care for a cloth face covering?","Current Answer":"It’s a good idea to [wash your cloth face covering](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/prevent-getting-sick/diy-cloth-face-coverings.html) frequently, ideally after each use. Have a bag or bin to keep cloth face coverings in until they can be laundered with detergent and hot water and dried on a hot cycle. If you must re-wear your cloth face covering before washing, wash your hands immediately after putting it back on and avoid touching your face. Discard cloth face coverings that:\\n\\n*   No longer cover the nose and mouth\\n\\n*   Have stretched out or damaged ties or straps\\n\\n*   Cannot stay on the face\\n\\n*   Have holes or tears in the fabric \\n\\n## **Insurance & cost**","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Cloth face covering, Mask, PPE","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"117"},{"Question":"I want to get screened or tested for COVID-19. I have insurance, but what will this cost me out-of-pocket?","Current Answer":"It should be free. The state agencies that regulate health care in California have mandated that all full-service insurance plans (including Medi-Cal) waive copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles for medically necessary screening and testing for COVID-19. This includes emergency room, urgent care, or provider office visits when the purpose of the visit is to be screened and tested for COVID-19.","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"Nothing. You can check your symptoms using the Symptom Screener or by contacting your doctor through telehealth. Virul testing for COVID-19 is covered by insurance, medicare, medi-cal, or state.","potential tags":"Insurance, Med-Cal, Medicare, Coverage, Benefit","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"119"},{"Question":"I have a concern or complaint about getting care for COVID-19 under my health insurance. What can I do?","Current Answer":"If you are having trouble accessing care, or were inappropriately charged cost-sharing for medically necessary screening and testing for COVID-19, follow up directly with your health plan by calling the member phone number listed on your health plan card. If your health plan doesn’t resolve the issue, contact the [California Department of Managed Health ](https://www.healthhelp.ca.gov/)[Care](https://github.com/cagov/covid19/issues/www.HealthHelp.ca.gov) (DMHC) Help Center for assistance at 1-888-466-2219.","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Insurance, Med-Cal, Medicare, Coverage, Benefit","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"120"},{"Question":"Do Medicare or Medicare Advantage Plans cover coronavirus tests or coronavirus antibody tests?","Current Answer":"Yes. Both [Medicare](https://www.medicare.gov/medicare-coronavirus) and [Medicare Advantage Plans](https://www.medicare.gov/sign-up-change-plans/types-of-medicare-health-plans/medicare-advantage-plans) cover [coronavirus tests](https://www.medicare.gov/coverage/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-tests) and [antibody ](https://www.medicare.gov/coverage/coronavirus-disease-2019-covid-19-antibody-test)tests, with no out-of-pocket costs.","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Insurance, Medicare, Medicare Advantage Plans, Coverage, Benefit","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"121"},{"Question":"Can I use telehealth if I am on Medicare?","Current Answer":"Yes. Medicare has temporarily expanded its coverage of [telehealth services (medical care via phone, video chat, or online portal)](https://www.medicare.gov/coverage/telehealth) to respond to the current Public Health Emergency. You can now use a wide range of communication tools (including smartphone) from home to interact with a range of providers, like doctors, nurse practitioners, clinical psychologists, licensed clinical social workers, physical therapists, occupational therapists, and speech language pathologists. If you have original Medicare, you can get many services without a copayment through [telehealth,](https://covid19.ca.gov/telehealth/) including evaluation and management visits (common office visits), mental health counseling, and preventive health screenings.\\n\\nIf you have a [Medicare Advantage Plan](https://www.medicare.gov/sign-up-change-plans/types-of-medicare-health-plans/medicare-advantage-plans), you have access to these same benefits. Many plans offer additional [telehealth](https://covid19.ca.gov/telehealth/) benefits and expanded benefits, like meal delivery or medical transport services. Check with your plan about your coverage and costs.\\n\\n## **Information for healthy living**","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Telehealth, Telemedicine, Insurance, Medicare, Medicare Advantage Plans, Coverage, Benefit","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"122"},{"Question":"I am nervous or scared. What can I do?","Current Answer":"You are not alone. The California Surgeon General released [two playbooks for managing stress](https://covid19.ca.gov/manage-stress-for-health/#top) and tips for care-givers and kids. If you feel like you need to talk to someone and want emotional support see this [list of resources](https://covid19.ca.gov/resources-for-emotional-support-and-well-being/#top).","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Mental health, Managing stress, Emotional Support","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"123"},{"Question":"My safety net eligibility (like CalFresh, Medi-Cal) is expiring and I am under the statewide shelter in place order for COVID-19. Do I need to renew my eligibility now?","Current Answer":"**No, you will not need to renew for 90 days.** Governor Gavin Newsom issued an [executive order](https://www.gov.ca.gov/2020/03/18/governor-newsom-issues-executive-order-to-protect-ongoing-safety-net-services-for-most-vulnerable-californians-during-covid-19-outbreak/) to ensure that health care, food assistance, and in-home supportive services continue during the COVID-19 outbreak.\\n\\nThe order waives eligibility re-determinations for 90 days for participants in:\\n\\n*   Medi-Cal health coverage\\n\\n*   CalFresh food assistance\\n\\n*   CalWORKs\\n\\n*   Cash Assistance for Immigrants\\n\\n*   In-Home Supportive Services","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Safety net, Medi-Cal, CalFresh, CalWORKs, Immigrants, Supportive Services","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"124"},{"Question":"What if I need to visit a health care provider?","Current Answer":"If you have [coronavirus symptoms](https://covid19.ca.gov/symptoms-and-risks/#top), please contact your doctor through [telehealth](https://covid19.ca.gov/telehealth/) or use the [Symptom Screener](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/symptoms-testing/symptoms.html?CDC_AA_refVal=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cdc.gov%2Fcoronavirus%2F2019-ncov%2Fsymptoms-testing%2Findex.html) self-checker.\\n\\nIf you have other illnesses or chronic conditions, use [telehealth](https://covid19.ca.gov/telehealth/) to get care from home.\\n\\nIf you need to go to the hospital, call ahead so they can prepare for your arrival. If you need to call 911, tell the 911 operator the exact symptoms you are experiencing so the ambulance provider can prepare to treat you safely.","Proposed revised question":"What if I need to visit my doctor or health care provider?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"health care, healthcare, provider, doctor, appointment","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"104"},{"Question":"Can I get my prescriptions filled?","Current Answer":"Yes. You may leave your home to obtain prescription medications or cannabis from dispensaries with medical permits.\\n\\nYou can contact your doctor through [telehealth](https://covid19.ca.gov/telehealth/) to get a new prescription or adjust your existing prescriptions.","Proposed revised question":"Can I leave my house to get my perscriptions filled?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"health care, healthcare, provider, doctor, prescription, RX, cannabis, medical cannabis","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"106"},{"Question":"I am an older Californian who is isolating at home and I need non-urgent assistance. What can I do?","Current Answer":"You can call the statewide hotline for older Californians at [833-544-2374](tel:1-833-544-2374) for your non-urgent medical needs, to get meals delivered, track down prescriptions and more. The most important thing you can do is stay home for your health and wellbeing. If you are experiencing an emergency please call 911.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"108"},{"Question":"How can I make sure the older Californians in my life are safe and healthy during the stay home order?","Current Answer":"You should check in on your older neighbors and loved ones with a call, text or physically distanced door knock to make sure they are okay. You can also teach them how to FaceTime, Zoom, Google Duo or use Facebook video to communicate. The most important thing you can do is to keep in touch with older loved ones for their mental health and safety.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"107"},{"Question":"Can I visit loved ones in the hospital, nursing home, skilled nursing facility, or other residential care facility?","Current Answer":"Generally no. There are limited exceptions, such as if you are going to the hospital with a minor who is under 18 or someone who is developmentally disabled and needs assistance. For most other situations, the order prohibits visitation to these kinds of facilities. This is difficult, but necessary to protect hospital staff and other patients. Check the [frequently asked questions for friends and family with a loved one in a skilled nursing or residential care facility](https://www.aging.ca.gov/download.ashx?lE0rcNUV0zaaXLD5JZ%2f6Uw%3d%3d) for more detailed information.\\n\\n### Outdoor recreation","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"110"},{"Question":"What do taxpayers need to do if they want to take advantage of relief from the California Department of Tax and Fee Administration?","Current Answer":"Interested taxpayers should contact CDTFA by visiting the [CDTFA website](http://cdtfa.ca.gov/) or calling [800-400-7115](tel:[800-400-7115]).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"tax relief","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"125"},{"Question":"When will taxpayers start on these payment plans?","Current Answer":"Given that the April deadline to file and pay sales and use tax returns has been extended to late July for all but the largest taxpayers, CDTFA expects that most participating taxpayers will begin their payment arrangements in late July of this year.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"tax relief, sales, use, use tax,","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"126"},{"Question":"How will the payment plans work?","Current Answer":"Qualifying sales and use taxpayers with deferred liabilities up to $50,000 will pay their tax due in 12 equal monthly installments. No interest or penalties will be assessed against the liability.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"127"},{"Question":"Is this only for tax payments due for the 1st quarter of 2020?","Current Answer":"If taxpayers choose to use this program to distribute the burden of their May or June prepayments or their July return, CDTFA will work to accommodate those taxpayers.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"128"},{"Question":"What if taxpayers owe more than the $50,000 limit on the relief?","Current Answer":"The maximum amount that any taxpayer can defer interest-free under this relief effort is $50,000.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"129"},{"Question":"What if taxpayers with more than $5 million in annual taxable sales need this relief?","Current Answer":"We recognize that some taxpayers, particularly in low margin businesses, with annual taxable sales over $5 million may also need this relief. Those taxpayers are encouraged to reach out to CDTFA, which will work with them to provide relief where appropriate.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"130"},{"Question":"Is the deadline for filing California tax returns extended?","Current Answer":"Yes. All California taxpayers (individuals and businesses) can file and pay by July 15, 2020.\\n\\nSee [information from the CA Franchise Tax Board](https://www.ftb.ca.gov/about-ftb/newsroom/news-releases/2020-3-state-postpones-tax-deadlines-until-july-15-due-to-the-covid-19-pandemic.html) for more information.","Proposed revised question":"removed from page","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"Scrape this answer from content above accordions on this page","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"other (not accordion)","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/taxes/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"83"},{"Question":"Is the deadline for filing California tax returns extended?","Current Answer":"Yes. All California taxpayers (individuals and businesses) can file and pay by July 15, 2020. See [information from the CA Franchise Tax Board](https://www.ftb.ca.gov/about-ftb/newsroom/news-releases/2020-3-state-postpones-tax-deadlines-until-july-15-due-to-the-covid-19-pandemic.html) for more information.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"tax, taxes, business, businesses, personal, pay, due, due date, file, filing, extended, taxpayers","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"131"},{"Question":"What is a loan guarantee?","Current Answer":"A loan guarantee is a credit enhancement that helps mitigate the risk assumed by a lending institution when making a loan. With the Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program, IBank agrees to guarantee up to 95% of the loan, removing the barriers to capital that often exist for small business borrowers that may not otherwise be eligible for traditional lending. This program also can assist those who may not be eligible for a U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA) loan.","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Business, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"132"},{"Question":"Who is eligible to apply?","Current Answer":"Small business entities that have been affected by loss, damage or other economic injury due to the COVID-19 pandemic and meet the program’s eligibility requirements.","Proposed revised question":"Who is eligible to apply for small business Disaster Relief Loan Gurantee Program?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Business, Eligible, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"133"},{"Question":"What do you consider a small business?","Current Answer":"The business must have between 1-750 employees and be established as an entity, including:\\n\\n*   Sole Proprietor – Individual using legal name as business name that files a Schedule C, Schedule F, or has a fictitious business name or DBA statement\\n\\n    *   If the loan appears to be in the name of an individual, evidence of Sole Proprietorship will be required and may include a Schedule C, Schedule F, Seller’s Permit, and/or fictitious business name or DBA statement\\n\\n*   Limited Liability Company \\n\\n*   Cooperative\\n\\n*   Corporation\\n\\n*   Partnership\\n\\n*   S-Corporation\\n\\n*   Not-for-profit\\n\\nThe program will not accept an *individual* as the borrower. It is permissible for an individual to be a guarantor or co-borrower on the loan, but the primary borrower must be a small business. It does not consider citizenship or immigration status for eligibility requirements**,** as long as the entity/individual meets the above criteria. Trucking owners/operators are eligible as long as they are registered as a legal business entity.\\n\\n**AND**\\n\\n*   The business activity must be eligible under the program and in one of the industries listed in the [North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) codes list](http://www.census.gov/eos/www/naics), and\\n\\n*   It must be located in a declared disaster area. A major disaster area declaration was made for the state of California on March 22, 2020 in regards to the COVID-19 pandemic.","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"134"},{"Question":"What are excluded businesses?","Current Answer":"Businesses that are not eligible include passive real estate businesses (rental income, etc.).","Proposed revised question":"What are excluded businesses for small business Disaster Relief Loan Gurantee Program?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Excluded, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"135"},{"Question":"Can I apply for a loan guarantee only if I am ineligible for federal disaster fund financing, such as a SBA loan?","Current Answer":"Yes, this program is designed for those who do not qualify for federal programs.","Proposed revised question":"Can I apply for a small business Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee even if I am ineligible for federal disaster fund financing, such as a SBA loan?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Gurantee, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"136"},{"Question":"How much can I borrow?","Current Answer":"The Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program allows a maximum loan of $1.25 million and a maximum guarantee of $1 million. To serve as many California small businesses as possible, the COVID-19 disaster program is focused on serving small businesses, especially those in low-wealth and immigrant communities with needs from $500 to $50,000.","Proposed revised question":"How much can I borrow under the Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Borrow, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"137"},{"Question":"What are the loan terms?","Current Answer":"The length of the loan can be negotiated with your lender, but the guarantee is good for up to seven years. The interest rate and loan criteria will be determined by the lender and could depend on the credit strength of the business. The guarantee is designed to lower the interest rate in exchange for a higher guarantee to your lender.","Proposed revised question":"What are the loan terms under the Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Loan Terms, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"138"},{"Question":"How can I apply?","Current Answer":"The Small Business Finance Center partners with Community Development Financial Institutions (CDFIs), Community Lending Institutions, and Financial Development Corporations (FDCs) to provide loan guarantees for small businesses.  To apply,\\n\\n*   View the [list of FDCs and participating lenders](http://www.ibank.ca.gov/small-business-finance-center/) interested in this Small Business Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program. \\n\\n*   Contact the lender on the list nearest to your business to apply.","Proposed revised question":"How can I apply for a loan under the Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Apply, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"139"},{"Question":"What is the timing for the funding of loans?","Current Answer":"The program is in place and businesses can apply immediately. Once you provide your lender with complete information, you could be funded in a matter of days.","Proposed revised question":"What is the timing for the funding of loans under the Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Timing, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"140"},{"Question":"What can the money be used for?","Current Answer":"The funds are meant to help small businesses through this challenging time. Loan proceeds can be used for business continuance or to cure “economic injury” as a result of COVID-19.","Proposed revised question":"What can the money under the Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program be used for?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Business Continuance, Economic Injury, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"141"},{"Question":"How will this program assist low-wealth and minority communities?","Current Answer":"By working with the Community Development Financial Institutions (CDFIs) throughout the state of California, this disaster relief program can play an important role in generating economic growth and opportunity in some of our most distressed communities. CDFIs and mission-based lenders play a vital role across the state and have experience steering lending and investment to where it is needed and will matter the most, in particular in low-wealth and immigrant communities. CDFIs and our partner Financial Development Corporations (FDCs) that process the loan guarantees are embedded in communities across the state, speak several languages, and are invested in the community successfully managing its way through this pandemic.","Proposed revised question":"How will the Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program assist low-wealth and minority communities?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Low Wealth, Minority Communities, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"142"},{"Question":"Are faith-based businesses eligible for this loan guarantee program?","Current Answer":"Faith-based businesses (non-profit or otherwise) that have business activity outside of worship are eligible as long as they are a legal business that has been affected by the COVID-19 pandemic.\\n\\n### **U.S. Small Business Administration Stimulus Programs**","Proposed revised question":"Are faith-based businesses eligible for the Small Business Finance Center’s Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Loan, Relief, Small Business, Low Wealth, Faith-based, Eligible, Disaster Relief Loan Guarantee Program","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"143"},{"Question":"What SBA programs are available to small businesses right now?","Current Answer":"The U.S. SBA offers the **Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) **and **Economic Injury Disaster Loan and Advance (EIDL and EIDL Advance)**.\\n\\nMore about **Paycheck Protection Program (PPP)**:\\n\\nThe SBA has resumed accepting PPP loan applications from approved lenders. The PPP is a loan program for small businesses, self-employed, independent contractors, nonprofits with a maximum of 500 employees, and it is intended to keep workers paid and employed. The loan amount is calculated based on payroll expenses with a maximum amount of $10 million at a rate of 1% for up to 2 years. The loan is forgivable if 75% of the loan amount is used for payroll, and no employees are laid off, or if laid-off employees are rehired before June 30, 2020. In addition to payroll costs, allowable expenses include mortgage interest, rent, and utilities. Submit your application as soon as possible, even if you need to rehire employees that have been laid off. Check the [Fact Sheet](https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/PPP--Fact-Sheet.pdf?mod=article_inline) and [Frequently Asked Questions](https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/Paycheck-Protection-Program-Frequently-Asked-Questions.pdf), and see [SBA.gov](https://www.sba.gov/funding-programs/loans/coronavirus-relief-options/paycheck-protection-program#section-header-0) for more details. You must apply directly through a lender. [Find a PPP lender in your area](https://www.sba.gov/paycheckprotection/find) to contact right away.\\n\\nMore about **Economic Injury Disaster Loan and Advance (EIDL and EIDL Advance):**\\n\\nAs of May 4, the U.S. SBA is accepting new applications from agricultural businesses only, and will continue to process **EIDL Loan and Advance applications** already submitted on a first come, first-served basis from all businesses. Check the U.S. SBA’s [Disaster Loan Applications website](https://www.sba.gov/page/disaster-loan-applications#section-header-0) for more information.\\n\\nThe EIDL is a direct loan for up to $2 million at a rate of 3.75% for small businesses and 2.75% for nonprofits. Applicants can get an **Advance **of up to $10,000 upon request within days of a successful application. This advance doesn’t have to be repaid. [Apply directly with the SBA](https://covid19relief.sba.gov/#/). For questions, you can contact SBA’s Customer Service Line at [1-800-659-2955](http://tel[1-800-659-2955]) / 1-800-877-8339 (TTY), or send an email to [disastercustomerservice@sba.gov](mailto:disastercustomerservice@sba.gov).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"144"},{"Question":"Which banks are offering the Paycheck Protection Program forgivable loans?","Current Answer":"Interested borrowers can contact any SBA participating bank, credit union, or nonprofit lenders to apply for the [PPP](https://www.sba.gov/funding-programs/loans/coronavirus-relief-options/paycheck-protection-program). For more information, contact your local bank or reach out to [SBA’s local district offices](https://www.sba.gov/local-assistance/find/?type=SBA%20District%20Office&pageNumber=1) for assistance.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"145"},{"Question":"Where do I find more information on allowable expenses for a forgivable loan under the Paycheck Protection Program?","Current Answer":"You can find this on the Paycheck Protection Program’s Loan Forgiveness Application. The application provides detailed instructions on how to apply for forgiveness of PPP loans. Once your business has expended the PPP funds and is ready to pursue loan forgiveness, please review the [Loan Forgiveness Application](https://content.sba.gov/sites/default/files/2020-05/3245-0407%20SBA%20Form%203508%20PPP%20Forgiveness%20Application.pdf) and consult with your accountant, lender, or one of California’s [small business centers](https://business.ca.gov/advantages/small-business-innovation-and-entrepreneurship/how-we-can-help/covid-19-resources-map/) for assistance.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"146"},{"Question":"How does a business know if it is eligible for an SBA loan or loan guarantee program?","Current Answer":"Small businesses with 500 employees or less are eligible to apply for the Paycheck Protection Program (PPP) and/or the Small Business Debt Relief Program. Small agricultural businesses are also eligible to apply for the Economic Injury Disaster Loan (EIDL) program and the EIDL Advance. Visit SBA’s comprehensive [COVID-19 support website](https://www.sba.gov/page/coronavirus-covid-19-small-business-guidance-loan-resources#section-header-4%20.) to find out more about SBA’s eligibility requirements for each program.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"147"},{"Question":"How do I reach SBA for any questions or assistance?","Current Answer":"SBA has district offices in California that are open to answer questions. You can use the [SBA’s Local Assistance Directory](https://www.sba.gov/local-assistance) to locate the office nearest you. You can also contact the SBA by phone at [1-800-659-2955](about:blank) / 1-800-877-8339 (TTY), or by email at [disastercustomerservice@sba.gov](mailto:disastercustomerservice@sba.gov).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"148"},{"Question":"How does a small business know which SBA loan or loan guarantee program is the right one? Can a small business apply to more than one?","Current Answer":"Call or email the SBA to find out which program is right for you. While businesses can apply for and receive more than one form of capital assistance through the SBA, they cannot be used for the same purpose. The SBA can advise you on your options. Call [1-800-659-2955](about:blank) / 1-800-877-8339 (TTY), or email [disastercustomerservice@sba.gov](mailto:disastercustomerservice@sba.gov).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"149"},{"Question":"How do I get SBA to cover my loan payments on my existing 7(a), 504, or microloan if I cannot pay due to COVID-19?","Current Answer":"SBA has a [Debt Relief program](https://www.sba.gov/funding-programs/loans/coronavirus-relief-options/sba-debt-relief) and will pay the principal and interest of existing SBA loans. Please contact your lender for information.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"150"},{"Question":"If I need help to figure out which program is best for me or to submit an application, where can I find support?","Current Answer":"California’s network of small business support centers can help you figure out which loans and programs are best for your business, develop resiliency strategies, and find other resources. Go to California’s [small business centers](https://business.ca.gov/advantages/small-business-innovation-and-entrepreneurship/how-we-can-help/covid-19-resources-map/) to find the closest center.\\n\\n### Employers","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"151"},{"Question":"How do I maintain a safe workplace?","Current Answer":"If your business is in an essential sector and remaining open during the stay home order, you should take steps to ensure the safety and health of your workers.\\n\\n*   Encourage sick employees to stay home.\\n\\n*   Establish routine cleaning throughout the workplace.\\n\\n*   Reduce travel. If possible, encourage video conferencing and limit larger gatherings.\\n\\n*   See [Cal/OSHA interim guidelines for general industry](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dosh/coronavirus/General-Industry.html).\\n\\n*   Follow [CDC guidance on keeping the workplace safe (pdf)](https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/downloads/workplace-school-and-home-guidance.pdf).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"needs revision","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"152"},{"Question":"How can I avoid laying off employees if my business is impacted by COVID-19?","Current Answer":"Apply for the [Unemployment Insurance (UI) Work Sharing Program](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Unemployment/Work_Sharing_Program.htm).\\n\\n### Stay Home Order","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/business-and-employers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"153"},{"Question":"Is there financial help for student loans?","Current Answer":"The [governor has ordered](https://www.gov.ca.gov/2020/04/23/governor-newsom-announces-additional-relief-for-californians-impacted-by-covid-19/) relief for students with federal loans. Check with your lender to see what options are available for you.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/education/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"174"},{"Question":"What if I don’t have internet access at home?","Current Answer":"Check with your local school district or college to see what resources are available for you.  List of providers offering free internet access currently:\\n\\n[Spectrum mobile](https://mobile.spectrum.com/support/article/360040980371/coronavirus-covid19-update)  has opened wifi hotspots and are working on assisting school districts with facilitating home internet access. \\n\\n[Comcast](https://corporate.comcast.com/covid-19) has opened free Xfinity WiFi hotspot access across the country. Xfinity has also paused data plans, late fees, and disconnects for the next 60 days. Families with limited income can receive internet services for free for the next 60 days (usually $9.95 per month). \\n\\n[AT&T](https://about.att.com/pages/COVID-19.html)  has opened all public WiFi hotspots and will not charge customers for any late fees or overages. AT&T also offers internet access for [$10/month for households on limited income](https://www.att.com/shop/internet/access/index.html?source=ECmj0000000000mbU&wtExtndSource=access#!/#%2F). \\n\\n[Low-cost Internet access plans](https://www.cde.ca.gov/ls/he/hn/availableinternetplans.asp) are also available.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/education/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"176"},{"Question":"How will students with disabilities receive services during school closures?","Current Answer":"The California Department of Education has released [guidance on distance learning](https://www.cde.ca.gov/ls/he/hn/distancelearning.asp)  to support schools in serving all students through this outbreak. This guidance includes recommendations to ensure equity and access for all students.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/education/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"177"},{"Question":"Will there be standardized testing? When?","Current Answer":"Probably not: on March 18, 2020, Governor Newsom issued an [executive order](https://www.gov.ca.gov/2020/03/18/governor-newsom-issues-executive-order-to-suspend-standardized-testing-for-students-in-response-to-covid-19-outbreak/)  to waive this year’s statewide testing for California’s more than 6 million students in K-12 schools, pending federal approval.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/education/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"178"},{"Question":"Program eligibility","Current Answer":"To be eligible for this program, you must:\\n\\n*   Work in a California healthcare facility \\n\\n    *   This includes medical transport providers and non-medical staff within health care facilities.\\n\\n*   This also includes workers in  California’s Health Corps or CAL MAT, as designated by the State.\\n\\n*   Have presumed exposure to COVID-19\\n\\n    *   This facility needs to be documented by a state or county public health official or medical professional to house COVID-19 positive patients.\\n\\n    *   Or healthcare workers who test positive for COVID-19 but do not require hospitalization\\n\\n*   Be unable to self-isolate or quarantine at home","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"179"},{"Question":"How to reserve a room","Current Answer":"*   Call [1-877-454-8785](tel:877-454-8785) to complete a screening process. Do not share personal health information. \\n\\n*   Show your healthcare facility employee identification at check-in. \\n\\n*   Provide a credit card or another form of deposit at check-in. \\n\\n*   The Program does not include extra services from the hotel, such as food, room service, valet, parking, or laundry. You will be responsible for incidentals.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"180"},{"Question":"Program details","Current Answer":"*   For the purposes of this program, “healthcare facility” does not include in-home support services (IHSS).\\n\\n*   Cost:\\n\\n    *   If you make less than $250,000, you are eligible for a room at no charge. \\n\\n    *   If you make $250,000 or more, you are eligible for a discounted room. Rates depend on the offers provided by participating hotels.\\n\\n*   FEMA has approved this program for emergency, non-congregate sheltering, and has advised the State that healthcare workers meeting these criteria are considered an eligible population for Non-Congregate Shelter (NCS) reimbursement.\\n\\nMeet these criteria? Call to reserve a room now: [1-877-454-8785](tel:877-454-8785)\\n\\n## Questions and answers","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"181"},{"Question":"Am I allowed to work during the outbreak?","Current Answer":"It depends what your job is. Workers in [essential sectors](https://covid19.ca.gov/essential-workforce/) are allowed to work during the Stay Home Order.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"164"},{"Question":"Am I allowed to work during the outbreak?","Current Answer":"It depends what your job is. Workers in [essential sectors (pdf)](https://covid19.ca.gov/img/EssentialCriticalInfrastructureWorkers.pdf) are allowed to work during the [stay home order](https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/#top). And anyone is allowed to work from their home that has arranged to do so with their employer.","Proposed revised question":"keep as is","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"This has been revised/live now: \r\nIt depends what your job is. Workers in essential sectors (pdf) are allowed to work during the stay home order. And anyone is allowed to work from their home that has arranged to do so with their employer. \r\nFor information on businesses and industry sectors that are allowed to operate in Stage 2 of reopening, visit statewide industry guidance. \r\nSome businesses and industry sectors may be open in counties that have received state approval to move further in Stage 2 of reopening, but are not yet permitted to reopen statewide. Visit county variance to learn more.","potential tags":"allowed to work, can i work, work during outbreak","Suggested changes":"n/a","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"accordion","Comments":"updated 5/26 to align with stage 2","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"182"},{"Question":"What can I do if my work hours are reduced because of COVID-19?","Current Answer":"You can [file an Unemployment Insurance claim](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Unemployment/Filing_a_Claim.htm).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"170"},{"Question":"What can I do if my work hours are reduced because of COVID-19?","Current Answer":"You can file for [Unemployment Insurance (UI)](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Unemployment/Filing_a_Claim.htm).","Proposed revised question":"keep as is","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"keep as is","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"183"},{"Question":"Do I need a note or certificate from a medical provider to file for unemployment?","Current Answer":"No, a medical certificate is not required. Here is more information on who is eligible for [Unemployment Insurance (UI)](https://www.edd.ca.gov/unemployment/eligibility.htm).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"168"},{"Question":"Do I need a note or certificate from a medical provider to file for unemployment?","Current Answer":"No, a medical certificate is not required.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"184"},{"Question":"How long will it take to process a claim for unemployment or insurance benefits and to receive a payment?","Current Answer":"After your claim is submitted, it will take at least three weeks to be processed. It may take longer if your information doesn’t match wage records or your identity can’t be verified. \\n\\nThe Governor has [waived the one-week waiting period](https://www.gov.ca.gov/2020/03/12/governor-newsom-issues-new-executive-order-further-enhancing-state-and-local-governments-ability-to-respond-to-covid-19-pandemic/). This means you can collect benefits for the first week that you were out of work or had reduced hours.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"172"},{"Question":"How long will it take to process a claim for unemployment or insurance benefits and to receive a payment?","Current Answer":"After your claim is submitted, it will take at least three weeks to be processed. It may take longer if your information doesn’t match wage records or your identity can’t be verified. \\n\\nThe Governor has [waived the one-week waiting period](https://www.gov.ca.gov/2020/03/12/governor-newsom-issues-new-executive-order-further-enhancing-state-and-local-governments-ability-to-respond-to-covid-19-pandemic/). This means you can collect benefits for the first week that you were out of work or had reduced hours.","Proposed revised question":"keep as is","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"keep as is","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"185"},{"Question":"What can I do if I miss work because of school closures?","Current Answer":"*   You can [file an Unemployment Insurance claim](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Unemployment/Filing_a_Claim.htm).\\n\\n*   Other options may be available. See [Benefits for Workers Impacted by COVID-19](https://www.labor.ca.gov/coronavirus2019/#chart).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"171"},{"Question":"What can I do if I miss work because of school closures?","Current Answer":"*   You can file for [Unemployment Insurance (UI)](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Unemployment/Filing_a_Claim.htm).\\n\\n*   Other options may be available. See [Benefits for Workers Impacted by COVID-19](https://www.labor.ca.gov/coronavirus2019/#chart).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"186"},{"Question":"What if I can’t work because I’m taking care of someone who’s sick or quarantined?","Current Answer":"*   You can use [paid sick leave](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dlse/paid_sick_leave.htm) if your job has it.\\n\\n*   You can [file a Paid Family Leave (PFL) claim](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Disability/How_to_File_a_PFL_Claim_in_SDI_Online.htm).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"169"},{"Question":"What if I can’t work because I’m taking care of someone who’s sick or quarantined?","Current Answer":"*   You may use [paid sick leave](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dlse/2019-Novel-Coronavirus.htm).  \\n\\n*   You can [file a Paid Family Leave (PFL) claim](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Disability/How_to_File_a_PFL_Claim_in_SDI_Online.htm).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"187"},{"Question":"What can I do if I can’t work because I’m sick or quarantined because of COVID-19?","Current Answer":"*   You can use [paid sick leave](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dlse/paid_sick_leave.htm) if your job has it. \\n\\n*   If you’re unable to work due to having or being exposed to COVID-19 you can [file a Disability Insurance (DI) claim](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Disability/How_to_File_a_DI_Claim_in_SDI_Online.htm).\\n\\n*   You may also file a [Worker’s Compensation Claim](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dwc/FileAClaim.htm) if you were exposed to coronavirus at work.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"165"},{"Question":"What can I do if I can’t work because I’m sick or quarantined because of COVID-19?","Current Answer":"*   You may be able to use [paid sick leave](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dlse/2019-Novel-Coronavirus.htm). \\n\\n*   If you’re unable to work due to having or being exposed to COVID-19 you can [file a Disability Insurance (DI) claim](https://www.edd.ca.gov/Disability/How_to_File_a_DI_Claim_in_SDI_Online.htm).\\n\\n*   You may also file a [Worker’s Compensation Claim](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dwc/FileAClaim.htm) if you suffered a COVID-19 illness that arose from an exposure during the course of your work.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"188"},{"Question":"What if I don’t have any available sick leave to use?","Current Answer":"The Labor and Workforce Development Agency has created a [chart detailing the available paid sick leave](https://www.labor.ca.gov/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/Side-by-Side-CA-Paid-Leave-FFCRA-Paid-Leave-4.9.20.pdf) under state and federal law and emergency paid family and medical leave under federal law.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"liz","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/workers/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"189"},{"Question":"How do I get mortgage relief and/or forbearance?","Current Answer":"You should contact and work directly with your mortgage servicer to learn about and apply for available relief. Please note that financial institutions and their servicers are experiencing high volumes of inquiries.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"156"},{"Question":"How long will the forbearance last?","Current Answer":"The terms of a forbearance will be agreed to between you and your mortgage service. Financial institutions will confirm approval of and terms of the forbearance program.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"157"},{"Question":"What effect will this have on my credit report?","Current Answer":"Financial institutions will not report derogatory information (*e.g.*, late payments) to credit reporting agencies but may report a forbearance, which typically does not alone negatively affect a credit score.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"158"},{"Question":"How long will these programs last?","Current Answer":"It is still unclear how severe or how long the COVID-19 impacts will be. Financial institutions have committed to necessary relief and will be assessing the ongoing conditions and necessity of continuing relief.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"159"},{"Question":"What if my financial institution isn’t offering this relief?","Current Answer":"At this time, JP Morgan Chase, US Bank, Wells Fargo and Citigroup, and nearly 200 state-chartered banks, credit unions are supporting these commitments. The state will welcome any other institution that would like to meet the moment and provide much-needed financial relief to Californians.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"160"},{"Question":"What if I already made a payment or was hit with a fee because of COVID-19?","Current Answer":"These measures go into effect as of March 25, 2020.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"161"},{"Question":"Is mortgage relief available to businesses?","Current Answer":"The relief is currently only available for residential mortgages.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"162"},{"Question":"What if my mortgage servicer is not communicative or cooperative?","Current Answer":"You can file a complaint with the Department of Business Oversight through the complaint form on the DBO website ([https://dbo.ca.gov/file-a-complaint/](https://gcc02.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fdbo.ca.gov%2Ffile-a-complaint%2F&data=02%7C01%7CManuel.Alvarez%40dbo.ca.gov%7Ce2673837ec6f42fce84508d7d114ed59%7Cd6910b1745b44b7bbb66cb7936fabafe%7C1%7C0%7C637207760136603083&sdata=VR6CdqCvrBGkfC%2Bm%2B6Yj9emco9ldVY5BLWSiLpe3f4c%3D&reserved=0)) or by contacting the DBO Consumer Services Office at (866) 275-2677 or (916) 327-7585 via email at [Ask.DBO@dbo.ca.gov](mailto:ASK.DBO@dbo.ca.gov).\\n\\n## Questions and answers for workers","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"163"},{"Question":"What kind of sick leave is available to me?","Current Answer":"Sick leave varies by employee. For details see [Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19): Frequently Asked Questions on laws enforced by the California Labor Commissioner’s Office](https://www.dir.ca.gov/dlse/2019-Novel-Coronavirus.htm).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"166"},{"Question":"What if my employer does not have paid sick leave?","Current Answer":"For those not able to secure paid leave, state [(California Family Rights Act)](https://ca.db101.org/ca/situations/workandbenefits/rights/program2c.htm) and federal laws [(Family and Medical Leave Act)](https://www.dol.gov/agencies/whd/fmla) may qualify you for up to 12 weeks of unpaid, job-protected leave per year.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"167"},{"Question":"Can I get child care during the stay home order?","Current Answer":"Yes, all child care facilities can open with necessary modifications. See the [Child care page](https://covid19.ca.gov/childcare/).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"child, child care, day care, babysitting","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"102"},{"Question":"Can I get child care during the stay home order?","Current Answer":"[Child care options](https://covid19.ca.gov/childcare/) are available if you are still reporting to work at an [essential job](https://covid19.ca.gov/essential-workforce/). If you are not working at an essential job, it is important to keep children at home.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/get-financial-help/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"173"},{"Question":"I am homeless and I may have come in contact with coronavirus. How can I self-isolate with nowhere to go and services closing down?","Current Answer":"Motel and hotel rooms may be available for families and individuals experiencing homelessness who have been exposed to COVID-19. [Contact](https://www.bcsh.ca.gov/hcfc/documents/coc_poc.pdf) your local homeless Continuum of Care to connect you to this service.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"ashley","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/housing-and-homelessness/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"190"},{"Question":"What if a provider says they have availability on MyChildCare.ca.gov but when I connect with them they have no space?","Current Answer":"The information on [MyChildCare.ca.gov](http://mychildcare.ca.gov/) will be updated twice each week but it is possible that vacancies are filled between updates. Contact your [local child care resource and referral agency](http://rrnetwork.org/family-services/find-child-care) to find more vacancies.","Proposed revised question":"What if a child care provider says they have availability on MyChildCare.ca.gov but when I connect with them they have no space?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"child, child care, day care, babysitting","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/childcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"193"},{"Question":"How can I find out more about the provider listed in MyChildCare.ca.gov?","Current Answer":"[MyChildCare.ca.gov](http://mychildcare.ca.gov/) includes each provider’s facility/license number, which can be searched at[ CDSS Community Care Licensing Database](https://www.ccld.dss.ca.gov/carefacilitysearch/) for information on inspections, complaints, and more.","Proposed revised question":"How can I find out more about the child care provider listed in MyChildCare.ca.gov?","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"child, child care, day care, babysitting","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/childcare/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"194"},{"Question":"Can my babysitter still come to the house?","Current Answer":"Yes, a child care worker can come to your home if necessary and should adhere to basic prevention guidelines (e.g. handwashing for at least 20 seconds, physical distancing, staying home if feeling ill).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"child, child care, day care, babysitting","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/stay-home-except-for-essential-needs/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"103"},{"Question":"What are the restrictions in my area?","Current Answer":"While each county may have different restrictions, it is important to stay home as much as possible. If you do go out, stay 6 feet away from others who are not in your household and wear a cloth mask. Your actions save lives. Learn more about the state’s roadmap to recovery and the list of counties who have met the criteria for stage 2.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"restrictions, county,","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"","IsContextOnly":"","Prompts":"","QnaId":""},{"Question":"How are we helping the homeless?","Current Answer":"Each county and local government in California has increased resources to protect people experiencing homelessness during COVID-19. Financial protections were added to prevent others from losing their homes during the outbreak.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Kayla","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"","IsContextOnly":"","Prompts":"","QnaId":""},{"Question":"When is the disaster relief assistance available?","Current Answer":"Individuals may begin applying on May 18, 2020. Assistance will be available until the funding is spent or until June 30, 2020, at the latest. Applicants will be considered on a first-come, first-served basis. Applicants may only apply with the nonprofit organization(s) in their county of residency.\\n\\n**Please note:**\\n\\n*   Funding is limited, and disaster relief application services and assistance are not guaranteed.\\n\\n*   Nonprofit organizations will not be assisting individuals before May 18. Individuals *should not* contact them ahead of time regarding disaster relief assistance.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"370"},{"Question":"Who is eligible for this disaster relief assistance?","Current Answer":"Eligible individuals must be able to provide information that they:\\n\\n*   Are an undocumented adult (person over the age of 18)\\n\\n*   Are not eligible for federal COVID-19 assistance, like the CARES Act stimulus payments or pandemic unemployment benefits, and\\n\\n*   Have experienced hardship as a result of COVID-19.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"371"},{"Question":"Can getting this assistance affect my ability to get a green card or to become a U.S. Citizen? Will receiving it make me a public charge?","Current Answer":"This disaster relief assistance is not means-tested and is one-time assistance. The federal government does not list this assistance as a public benefit for a public charge consideration. However, USCIS has not issued specific guidance related to this assistance.\\n\\nIf you have questions about your immigration status and this program, please consult an attorney. A list of free and low-cost immigration services providers is available in the [Guide for Immigrant Californians (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/img/wp/listos_covid_19_immigrant_guidance_en_daf.pdf).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"372"},{"Question":"Is the personal information I provide to the nonprofits protected?","Current Answer":"Your information is only used to confirm eligibility and provide the assistance. No personal information (like name or address) will be given to any government agency. Only general information like age, gender, and preferred language will be shared with the State of California.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"373"},{"Question":"How do I apply?","Current Answer":"The California Department of Social Services (CDSS) has identified non-profit where you can apply for disaster assistance. Find the [nonprofit where you can apply in your area](https://cdss.ca.gov/inforesources/immigration/covid-19-drai).\\n\\nApply *no sooner than May 18, and only to the organization in your area.* They will assist you with applying, confirm your eligibility, and deliver a payment card if you are approved. Applications will be considered on a first-come, first-served basis.\\n\\nFunding is limited, and disaster relief application services and assistance are not guaranteed.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"374"},{"Question":"How many people in a household can receive this assistance?","Current Answer":"A maximum of two adults per household can qualify for this assistance, for a total of $1,000 per household. A household is defined as individuals who live, shop, and prepare meals together.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"375"},{"Question":"How do eligible individuals receive this assistance?","Current Answer":"You will get a payment card either in person or through the mail. The organization in your area can give you more information.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"376"},{"Question":"How long do I have to apply?","Current Answer":"Payments will be distributed beginning on May 18, 2020. They will continue until the $75 million in funding is spent, or until June 30, 2020 at the latest. We expect that this disaster relief assistance will run out very quickly. Apply as soon as you can, but not before May 18.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"377"},{"Question":"If I am unable to apply for this program, are there other organizations that can help me?","Current Answer":"Yes. The California Immigrant Resilience Fund is raising $50 million to provide cash assistance to undocumented Californians who are ineligible for other COVID-19 programs. Visit the [California Immigrant Resilience Fund](http://www.immigrantfundca.org) website to see if you can benefit from this program.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"378"},{"Question":"What other government programs may I be eligible for during the COVID-19 pandemic?","Current Answer":"Check the [Guide for Immigrant Californians (PDF)](https://covid19.ca.gov/img/wp/listos_covid_19_immigrant_guidance_en_daf.pdf). It has information about jobs, wages, benefits, and small business and housing support.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"oriel","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/guide-immigrant-californians/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"379"},{"Question":"Is in-language assistance available?","Current Answer":"Your local health department will provide translation support in many different languages to help with communication.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Peggy","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/contact-tracing/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"391"},{"Question":"Who should get tested?","Current Answer":"Testing is recommended for close contacts of individuals who have or are suspected of having COVID-19 and people who are exhibiting symptoms. See the [testing page for details](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/#top).","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Peggy","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/contact-tracing/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"392"},{"Question":"How do I find a testing location?","Current Answer":"To learn more about testing and care, visit the [testing webpage](https://covid19.ca.gov/testing-and-treatment/). You can also search for testing locations using your zip code. \\n\\n**Tips to protect others around you:**\\n\\nIf you are confirmed to have COVID-19, it is important to quarantine yourself from others, so they do not get sick. It will be recommended that you stay in a separate room and use a separate bathroom if possible. It’s important to disinfect frequently touched surfaces and items to prevent spreading the virus. \\n\\nPeople you live with are considered close contacts and will be recommended to get tested. \\n\\n**How to find supportive resources:** \\n\\nYour local public health department can connect you to testing, medical care and additional supportive resources. Depending on resources, your local public health department may be able to find options for you to live in a place outside your home to assist you in safely recovering during self-isolation.\\n\\nIn addition, you can find resources for you and your family on this website. Resources for immigrant Californians can also be found on the [Guide for Immigrant Californians](https://covid19.ca.gov/img/wp/listos_covid_19_immigrant_guidance_en_daf.pdf). \\n\\nYou can find childcare support by visiting [MyChildCare.ca.gov](http://mychildcare.ca.gov/) for information on all licensed center-based and family child care homes, including both private-pay and subsidized childcare. Children of essential workers are eligible to enroll in subsidized Emergency Childcare, subject to capacity and eligibility requirements. Your[ local child care resource and referral agency](https://rrnetwork.org/index.php?p=family-services/find-child-care) can answer more questions about child care subsidies.","Proposed revised question":"","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"","potential tags":"","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Peggy","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/contact-tracing/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"393"},{"Question":"Some healthcare professions are not listed. Are health professionals who are not listed (e.g., Medical Technicians, Lab Technicians, etc.) eligible for the California Health Corps?","Current Answer":"California Health Corps are currently only accepting applications for the healthcare professions listed on the website. However, we are constantly re-evaluating our needs during this fluid situation and will open the registration for other professionals, if the need arises.","Proposed revised question":"N/A","Proposed revised answer for Quick answer":"N/A","potential tags":"Health Corps, Health Professionals, Volunteer, Technician","Suggested changes":"","Content captain":"Karim","Content type (accordion, other)":"","Comments":"","Source":"https://covid19.ca.gov/healthcorps/","Page Links":"","Revised (Y/N)":"","Metadata":"","SuggestedQuestions":"[]","IsContextOnly":"FALSE","Prompts":"[]","QnaId":"417"}]